In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of Doshi Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, Doshi Marvelous Designer is used in this tutorial.
Now you see the default interface of the software.
On the left side, there are two labels that can be switched between the main interface and the store.
Any content related to clothing production is completed in the main interface.
Switching to the store page, we can browse and buy products from Marvelous Designer stores in the software.
Back to the main interface page, on the left side is the library window.
Here you can view or quickly download the default files provided by Marvelous Designer.
In addition,
Click on the add button in the upper right corner of the library window.
You can add a file folder to the library window on your computer,
so that you can quickly download it when using Marvelous Designer.
On the right side of the library window, there are 3D and 2D windows.
In the 3D window, you can lead a default or customized virtual model
and check the effect by putting on clothing for it.
In the 2D window, you can manually edit the version or modify the version according to your needs.
On the right side of the main interface, there is the material and attribute editor window.
In the attribute editor, you can see the attribute settings of any 3D or 2D window elements.
Since Marvelous Designer 11, the object window has been removed.
To do this, click on the arrow next to the window name,
you can open the download menu,
and select the window type you need to change.
Click on the add button in the upper right corner of the window,
you can copy an independent pop-up window.
You can also change the window type through the download menu.
You can drag it to the side window to make window combinations.
If you do this,
you can change the window by using the label at the bottom of the window.
The side window can be closed by clicking on the X button in the upper right corner of the window,
or by clicking on the arrow in the upper left corner to make a fold.
If the window is folded,
the window will appear on the side in the form of a label.
Click on the label again to cancel the fold.
The five buttons in the lower right corner of the screen are used to set the number of windows in the main workspace.
You can open up to four windows at the same time.
Every time you add a window, you will automatically add a 3D window.
If you activate multiple 3D windows at the same time,
you can use different tools in each 3D window.
In addition, the tool you choose in the 3D window will be linked to the 2D window.
Since there is only one 2D window in the software,
if you change the other windows to 2D windows,
it will call the 2D window location.
By clicking on the reset button in the lower right corner of the screen,
you can reset the screen to the original default setting.
After setting the custom layout,
you can exit the software.
After opening the software again,
you will still keep the custom layout while using it.
Click on the little triangle at the bottom of the screen,
and you can choose to open or fold the animation editor.